Matthew H. Morgan

874 Tice Place, Westfield, NJ 07090 - Mobile: (908) 251-1587 - Email:m.morgan4491@gmail.com

TECHNICAL SALES PROFESSIONAL

BIOMEDICAL ENGINEER, COMPLEX SALES, TECHNICAL INNOVATION

SUMMARY

Proven technical sales professional with experience in biomedical engineering, pharma, and mechanical systems. Strengths include understanding highly technical products and digital solutions, possessing the ability to explain complex operations in layman's terms, and articulating customer benefits, convincing them to buy. Have consistently delivered positive sales results exceeding territory targets, winning sales recognition awards, and being selected to mentor others in the organization. Recognized for strengths in communication and garnering customer's trust to provide best-in-class solutions and accelerate annual revenue growth. Acknowledged as an influential, tenacious, and innovative leader.

Unique Value:

- Growth Oriented
- Technical specialist digital and mechanical solutions
- Strategic Sales & Marketing
- Employee Training & Development

- Innovative Solutions
- Customer Relationship Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Medtronic (New Jersey)

Sales Representative – CRM

Mar 2021 - Present

Provided advanced technical support for cardiac rhythm and heart failure medical devices during device interrogations and implant procedures

- Passed the IBHRE CCDS-AP exam in July 2023
- Continue to drive leadless pacemaker implant growth with average QoQ growth of 12% in last three quarters, equating to an average revenue growth of 30% over that last three quarters
- Nominated for and successfully completed Medtronic's PRIME sales development program (August 2022-May 2023) one of 35 individuals selected nationally to participate in a rigorous 9 month instructor-lead course focusing on identifying strengths, persuasion skills, selling, managing a book of business, personal branding
- Maintained a high level of communication with physicians, hospital personnel, and patients to ensure successful patient outcomes including home monitoring set up and patient compliance, concerns relating to follow up visits, questions regarding traveling with a medical device, as well as moral support during a new phase of life for most patients
- Collaborated with team members daily to achieve the highest efficiency possible with scheduling device checks and implants based on region and travel time. Territory leads the district with smartphone app-based home monitoring adoption (33% territory with a district average of 15%)
- Coached and supported new hires in adjusting to a field-based position including reporting mileage correctly, how
 to access dashboard reports to achieve efficiency and target focus, appropriate goal setting for development, and
 inventory management

Ferguson Enterprises (Northeast Territory), NJ Technical Sales Representative Feb 2016 – Feb 2021 Responsible to drive growth in dynamic \$1.2 billion HVAC division. Earned loyalty of owners of large mechanical contractors to become a trusted advisor and business partner, successfully promoting technical products and innovative approaches to deliver sales growth.

- Successfully penetrated hyper-competitive New York City and Long Island markets growing share via targeted marketing and competitive intelligence, which culminated in 3 major acquisition.
- Developed innovative, pre-packaged copper pipe go-to-market strategy. Increased sales throughout district over 20x to \$2.5 million/yr while increasing margins. Approach adopted by plumbing division.

Matthew H. Morgan

874 Tice Place, Westfield, NJ 07090 - Mobile: (908) 251-1587 - Email:m.morgan4491@gmail.com

- Value engineered commercial projects to differentiate from competitors. Managed implementation scheduling to match project timelines, increasing contractor's job site effectiveness, minimizing stock and reducing waste.
- Fastest graduate of onboarding program to territory manager. Distinct assignment to train new hires in product knowledge, sales strategy, operations, and CRM/sales platform.

Key Performance Results:

- \$9 million sales exceeding \$7.2 million target by 25% despite adverse impact of pandemic
- Received prestigious Diamond Club Award in digital connected products #6 of 2,000 reps nationally
- Won 3-day fishing trip for outstanding sales performance in Honeywell/Resideo forced-air products
- Drove 30% of sales through the online platform improving order accuracy

Zingerman, Inc., NJ

Pharmaceutical Consultant

May 2015 – Dec 2015

- Conducted process capability and control analysis on pharmaceutical tablet manufacturing for scale up trials on four new products.
- Analyzed empirical test data to optimize tablet composition and coating quality.

EDUCATION

The College of New Jersey, Ewing, NJ

B.S. in Biomedical Engineering, 2014 (Dean's List)

Designed and built servo-controlled leg assist exoskeleton: Intuitive Leg Assist Device 2 (ILAD2) https://sites.google.com/site/ilad2project/

Liver Tissue Engineering: A Novel Approach to Development of Vascularized Hepatocyte Tissue Evaluated microneedle patch drug delivery to treat HPV compared to traditional injection methods

SKILLS / ACTIVITIES

Microsoft Word, Excel and PowerPoint, SolidWorks 3D Modeling, LabVIEW. Member of TCNJ's nationally ranked DIII Men's Swim Team 2009-2013 Men's Varsity Swim Team Assistant Coach 2013-2014 Season Completed an Ironman-distance Triathlon (140.6 miles) in Atlantic City June 2014 Surfing, yoga, avid outdoorsman